<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Blogging Kevin</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/</id><updated>2013-12-28T10:58:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Test Article Number 3</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/test-article-3/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-12-28T10:58:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2013-12-28:articles/test-article-3/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="test-title"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Test Title&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sddffsdfsdf
sdfsdfsd
fdsfsdfs
l&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Test Article Number 2</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/test-article-2/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-12-27T10:58:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2013-12-27:articles/test-article-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tite"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THajdkaldk
alkdlaskd
laksd
ka
sdka
lk
lk
l&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning to drive in Ontario? Beware of Contradictions</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/learning-to-drive-in-ontario-beware-of-contradictions/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-14T19:31:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2012-12-14:articles/learning-to-drive-in-ontario-beware-of-contradictions/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The process of learning to drive in an incredibly stressful one. From
reading about all sorts of hieroglyphic - looking symbols you've never
seen before, to being at the mercy of any one of the many questionable
driver trainers out there (I could probably be counted among them even
though I have good intentions). At some point, the process of learning
this massive undertaking may seem impossible, but it's not. Trust me on
that. What you can't trust is much of what you read either.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
A simple disclosure - I have been driving now for almost 21 years. I've
seen a great many things which I won't elaborate about here. What I have
also seen, is many friends and family going though the process of
learning to drive. One such unbelievable example is while working with
my sister Crystal as she was answering yet another confusing question.
This one related to how many demerit points are lost when you reverse in
a car without a seatbelt. Do you know the answer to that one?

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
Can you trust your Official MTO Driver Handbook to answer that question?
Let's see, I'm going to take the current version of this handbook and
show you.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;First, Page 29
- Regarding Seat Belts&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][image]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
Take a look at the above picture of page 29 of the handbook. It says
"Use your seatbelt always, even when you are sitting in a position with
an active airbag". Certainly seat belts are an important safety feature
of a car, and it would be reasonable to think you should be wearing them
"always". As a young driver learning this, you've read up to page 29 of
the "Official" Ministry of Transportation Handbook, so - more that being
proud of yourself - you assume this must be right. Right?

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
Now, I don't want to quibble with word meanings too much, but "always"
tends to mean all the time, or perhaps EVERY time. It's safe to say that
"always" would be a more definitive way of communicating "if your butt
is in the seat and the vehicle is moving, wear a seat belt".

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;Next, go to
Page 55 - Regarding Reversing&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][1]][1]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
The above is a picture of page 55 of the same handbook. It clearly
states "You don't have to wear a seat belt while backing up". This is a
clear and direct contradiction of previously stated "Use your seat belt
always". What is a person who might just be trying to figure out the
rules of the road do? Which is right? Why the intentional contradiction
in the first place?

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
The law does say this - in the Highway Traffic Act, the following
exemptions apply:

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
106.(5)Exemptions

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
You don’t have to wear a seat belt if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
\1) You’re driving in reverse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
So, one of these two points in the Handbook is correct. Let's hope they
work to make this handbook clearer for the learners. We need better
drivers on the road, not more laws!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Contradictions"></category><category term="Driving"></category><category term="Learn"></category><category term="Seat Belts"></category></entry><entry><title>Let the home buyer beware: When water heaters aren't cool</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/let-the-home-buyer-beware-when-water-heaters-arent-cool/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-15T15:01:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2012-03-15:articles/let-the-home-buyer-beware-when-water-heaters-arent-cool/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][image]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a new home owner, and as such, not an expert in real estate. With
all the things that happen when one buys a house, you'd be hard pressed
to understand every nuanced part of every deal. Today while looking at
some paperwork, I discovered how the previous homeowners pulled
something of a trick on me and how I should have been more diligent
about the process. Hopefully after seeing this, you'll be more watchful
of your own home buying process.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I do have egg on my face over this - but more than looking like a fool -
I wanted to share how others might avoid this sort of pain and
frustration in the future.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, a fellow from National Home Services came to the house trying to
sell (for the hundredth time) a new water heater. He was fairly rude and
I tried to be as courteous as I could. It appears there is no way to
stop these people from coming to your door. I had heard about National
Home Services, but did not really know much more than the fact that I
see them on my Enbridge bill. Since I had never signed a contract with
them, I would not be subject to the horror stories others mention. But,
I had always wondered why they are charging me for a water heater.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hDxU7g1BSVU/TzrohfOITVI/AAAAAAAACys/b_A5wQ5pLCo/s1600/QuickShot+2012-02-14+at+18.01.27.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hDxU7g1BSVU/TzrohfOITVI/AAAAAAAACys/b_A5wQ5pLCo/s1600/QuickShot+2012-02-14+at+18.01.27.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  What I see on my bill every month&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, today I took the step of calling them and asking what the nature of
my business with them was. The woman on the other end first asked for my
address and I gave it to her. Then she asked for my home sales agreement
- this was a little too much information to give out - so I refused this
request. She seemed quite perturbed by my refusal to provide
information. But, she was willing to assist and offered to send me the
current agreement they had that was in a previous owner's name. That
agreement was signed by the previous owner on July 15th, 2008. I took
over the house somewhere around August or September of 2008, so this
happened JUST before I moved in. The woman from National tells me this
contract is a 15 year contract and to get out of it, I would have to pay
a $575.00 cancellation fee.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-s3VUn-FrM3M/TzrpnxJx9TI/AAAAAAAACy8/3jI7-tFYd6I/s1600/shot_2142012_60628_pm.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-s3VUn-FrM3M/TzrpnxJx9TI/AAAAAAAACy8/3jI7-tFYd6I/s1600/shot_2142012_60628_pm.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  Hey, that's not me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the reason why the woman at National Home Services wanted to see my
agreement was because of one simple line that would either stick me for
the contract or allow me to get out of it. This is item #6 of a typical
contract that determines what stuff the new owner takes on. In my case
it says "Hot Water Tank".  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][3]][3]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you seeing this? Some of the more astute of you might be able to see
past my boneheadedness and see what's going on here. The previous owner,
in a pinch decided that the house sale would look much better with a
&lt;strong&gt;SHINY NEW&lt;/strong&gt; hot water heater decided to sign a 15 year contract with
National Home Services just before selling and then slyly include that
in the sales agreement passing it off to me. As a first time,
inexperienced home buyer, I didn't think to look for that, nor did I
figure it out until some time later.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this translate to money, you ask?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the life of this contract to National Home Services, I will have
paid &lt;strong&gt;$2,251.80&lt;/strong&gt;(or more considering increases). To continue and
finish the contract from today, I will need to pay &lt;strong&gt;$1,651.32&lt;/strong&gt; (or
more) for the rest of the term. To get out of the contract right now,
the minimum charge (cancellation fee) is &lt;strong&gt;$575.00&lt;/strong&gt;. Since National
Home Services doesn't even see me as a customer - I also get sales
calls!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparable water heater &lt;strong&gt;$553.00&lt;/strong&gt; + possibly &lt;strong&gt;$250.00&lt;/strong&gt; installation:
&lt;strong&gt;$803.00&lt;/strong&gt; + Taxes.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boy, do I feel stupid.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: red;"&gt;Update:&lt;/span&gt; After waiting close to a month
for a response about a water heater buyout - National Home Services
responded with this message on March 14th:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][4]][4]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$1,039.40&lt;/strong&gt; is steep, but it appears the best option I have for the
lifetime of the heater. This will (at least) save me &lt;strong&gt;$611.92&lt;/strong&gt; or more
for the lifetime of the water heater. This also gives me the option of a
direct replacement down the road (if I choose to go after a more
efficient model). Perhaps most important, I don't have to saddle the
next home owner with a ludicrous contract if the house is sold.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="National Home Services"></category><category term="Real Estate"></category><category term="Water Heater"></category></entry><entry><title>It's time to vote for REAL change. This October I vote Libertarian.</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/its-time-to-vote-for-real-change-this-october-i-vote-libertarian/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-10-11T16:40:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-10-11:articles/its-time-to-vote-for-real-change-this-october-i-vote-libertarian/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][image]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I want to make it clear, no matter what I say - my hope is that
you choose to do what is so important to our way of life. Please
&lt;strong&gt;vote&lt;/strong&gt; in this coming Ontario Provincial Election on October 6th, 2011
(click &lt;a href="http://fyed.elections.on.ca/fyed/en/form_page_en.jsp"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to find your electoral district) and make your &lt;strong&gt;voice&lt;/strong&gt;
heard.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, now it's time to talk about how I'll vote. In the past
Ontario elections I have voted Green party and if I were to go back
further, Liberal. This year none of those will get my vote.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I vote Liberation.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liberation? What's that, you say? Is that something to do with the
Liberals? No.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Liber- in Liberation comes from Liberty, not Liberal.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liberty is:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state of being free within society from oppressive restrictions
imposed by authority on one's way of life, behavior, or political
views&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the essence of this is that you know what's best for you your
family. &lt;strong&gt;No other authority can tell you what's best for you.&lt;/strong&gt; I can't
tell you what's best for you.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don't know why this isn't more popular. Just a couple days ago,
the candidate for the Oshawa Liberation party in Oshawa, &lt;a href="http://libertarian.on.ca/users/matthew-belanger"&gt;Matthew
Belanger&lt;/a&gt;, was nice enough to meet with me - and I asked him that very
question.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We're just not out there. It's hard to get the word out"  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll say.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's more than hard when you're considered what he calls a "fringe"
party. You likely won't see the Libertarians in any sort of provincial
debate or media platform. Last night's debate only included three
parties. What they're talking about is a massive, no, MONSTER shift in
policies from where we are now.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine completely privatized medicine? Privatized Education?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine all roads privatized?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine the end of welfare?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine the buying and selling beer and wine anywhere?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine taxes being a mere fraction of what they are now?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the Liberation party wants is for the Government to &lt;strong&gt;get the hell
out&lt;/strong&gt;of our lives (with the exception of a few things) and let us live
the way we see fit. They want to let us keep our money to do what we
think is best for ourselves, our family. Imagine a day when you start by
getting paid double what you have now (after all, &lt;a href="http://www.fraserinstitute.org/publicationdisplay.aspx?id=17626"&gt;tax freedom day&lt;/a&gt; is
in june). What would you do with it?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel it's time to make huge changes. The oppressively taxed, over
bureaucratic system we're a part of today is NOT working. We're part of
a culture of too much Government and too much entitlement.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: red;"&gt;UPDATE - October
11th, 2011&lt;/span&gt; - As it turns out - I live in the &lt;a href="http://www.wemakevotingeasy.ca/en/general-election-district-results.aspx?d=100"&gt;WHITBY-OSHAWA&lt;/a&gt;
riding and there was no Libertarian on the ballot. I was forced to vote
another party and vote for what I thought was best. I felt, this time
around, that we had very little time to prepare for this vote. The voter
turnout was extremely low - Christine Elliott of the PC party was the
winner.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Can you "do nothing"?</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/can-you-do-nothing/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-05T23:06:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-03-05:articles/can-you-do-nothing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I found a wonderful and fascinating &lt;a href="http://thesocietypages.org/socimages/2011/03/04/doing-nothing-an-experiment-in-norm-breaking-2/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+SociologicalImagesSeeingIsBelieving+(Sociological+Images:+Seeing+Is+Believing)"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on the Sociological
Images blog about the idea of doing nothing. That's right - just
standing motionless, with no facial expression, doing absolutely nothing
at all. The idea of taking 262 students, placing them in a public place
and have them just stand around like this (see video) seemed like a very
interesting idea. What are our reactions to seeing others break
society's norms and how do we feel as we're breaking them? How does our
norm of constantly being busy effect us as a society?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The experiment I mentioned was conducted at Georgia
Southern University by a lecturer named Nathan Palmer (see his
&lt;a href="http://www.sociologysource.com/home/2011/3/2/doing-nothing-learning-deviance.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;). This happened locally at the campus and, from what it seems
in the video, the students were confined to a fairly small space. Take a
look at this short video:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is doing nothing anyway? Try this: Go sit down on a chair or couch
and not pick up your phone, read anything, watch anything, or talk to
anyone. Try and sit, motionless, making no facial expressions, not
talking to anyone. You'll find that this is not only weird, this is
actually extremely difficult. Shortly you'll think of something to do or
your phone will ring or someone will call you. In our North American
society, one of the most pervasive social norms is our need to stay busy
all the time.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even acting busy works. I worked at Burger King for upwards of 8
years and one of the things we were told to do when tending to a
customer is to look busy. Yes, there are times when we would have
nothing but waiting for something to cook, but you could go and grab a
bag, go badger someone about how quickly they're making a sandwich or
generally just walk back and forth erratically. This tends to work for
people, because, while they wait for something, watching a person "act"
busy makes them feel like something will get done faster.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the example of an elevator button. Many of us will go up to an
elevator and press the button and stand there fixed in a stare on the
small screen that tells us where the elevator is. But, there are allot
of folks that will also continued to press that button with some sort of
intention that pressing the button repeatedly will make the elevator
move faster? Perhaps we do it just for something to do?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole idea of it being unacceptable in our society to do nothing is
underscored by our collective difficulty in maintaining a sense of calm.
I see many people everyday that can't seem to handle silence or have any
sense of patience (increasingly, this includes myself). When they have
to wait for an appointment, people need to have reading materials close
to them. When we wait in a line, we need to be using our smart phones
looking for updates of some sort. It seems as if our social norm of
being busy all the time my be starting to effect our health. I wonder if
there have been studies about this kind of thing? It wouldn't be too
much of a stretch to think that our need to be busy may correlate to
North America's &lt;a href="http://notsomuch.org/2010/11/the-decline-of-mental-health-in-america/"&gt;decline&lt;/a&gt; in mental health.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the kind of blockbuster news it would be to find out that all we
need for better mental health is just slow down or stop sometimes; You
probably don't need to go far to see examples of moments when you could
have taken advantage of stopping and didn't do it. One of the biggest
examples of this for me was when I spent two weeks backpacking in Panama
a few years ago. The trip took me to the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Blas_Islands"&gt;San Blas Islands&lt;/a&gt;, a
beautiful set of islands in the north of Panama. The island we were
staying at housed a few travellers and one family that did the cooking
for us. The rest fo the trip involved no more than eating food, taking
the 5 minute walk from edge to edge of the island and sleeping in your
hammock. Rather quickly, the power on all of my electronic devices ran
out and I had no actual books to read. This would have been the perfect
moment to embrace doing nothing, but I tended to want to leave as soon
as possible.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-bGzq7PWVFxU/TXK8jSMzr1I/AAAAAAAAA_0/z4FTXOz5P0Y/s1600/n847205293_2288912_3048.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-bGzq7PWVFxU/TXK8jSMzr1I/AAAAAAAAA_0/z4FTXOz5P0Y/s1600/n847205293_2288912_3048.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  Isla Robinson - one of the San Blas islands that I visited in 2008&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time passess, we all might benefit from using some of it to just sit
down, turn everything off and do nothing. Perhaps if more of us even did
nothing in public or while waiting for things, it would be less of an
unusual thing for people to do? Even more valuable for those of us that
don't meditate, the act of doing nothing may lead you closer to
understanding and even practicing meditation. Maybe not, but it would
make you one hell of a better driving companion on those long trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-LPNaP1Xl0fE/TXK-1Bh1vSI/AAAAAAAAA_4/zrdS_7YARAQ/s200/download.jpeg" /&gt;]: https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-LPNaP1Xl0fE/TXK-1Bh1vSI/AAAAAAAAA_4/zrdS_7YARAQ/s1600/download.jpeg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Norms"></category><category term="Nothing"></category><category term="Society"></category></entry><entry><title>From the airport looking out....</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/from-the-airport-looking-out/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-23T21:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-02-23:articles/from-the-airport-looking-out/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;
Have you ever wondered what it might look like if you were to take a
destination and look at it from the perspective of the actual airport?
Well, with the wonders of Google Earth on an iPad, I was able to see
what it might look like in La Paz, Boloivia. Enjoy!

![image][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="airport"></category><category term="google earth"></category></entry><entry><title>This one's gotta go</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/this-ones-gotta-go/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-14T03:26:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-02-14:articles/this-ones-gotta-go/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;
Thanks to the wonders of radiation (or whatever it is they hit you with
to get x-rays) - I now have a clearer picture of a tooth that has been
an annoyance for some time now. This is likley a baby tooth that never
decided to come out... what will fill the space is the subject of much
thought now.

![image][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dentist"></category><category term="teeth"></category><category term="xray"></category></entry><entry><title>The New, New Dominican in January 2011 - Part 3</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/the-new-new-dominican-in-january-2011-part-3/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-26T00:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-26:articles/the-new-new-dominican-in-january-2011-part-3/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final part to these three parts I have written, I would like to
make a compendium of pictures and videos gathered throughout the trip.
These pictures were taken mainly by myself using a Canon t1i DLSR camera
or using my smartphone (an HTC G2). Some fo these picture were also
taken by my travel companion, Julio, using his compact digital camera.
You may wish to skip much of the commentary and just go to the
respective locations and browse through &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/101717868435732698611/2011JanDominican?authkey=Gv1sRgCNW2h5618vjjXg&amp;amp;feat=directlink"&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/calwellmedia"&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; - by
all means. For more visual delight, read on.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;The
Videos&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Punta Cana - I arrived to see an incredible sight - something I had
never seen before! I was treated to that of a five star resort. Take a
look at this amazing room and the amenities in it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some have said that this is nto so exciting - I disagree! THe sand in
Punta Cana is just amazing. Take a look for yourself and decide.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up in Puerto Plata, I took in a baseball with Davi. This game was so
exciting that, at one point, the team and the crowd got into a big
fight.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
I was also able to get a ride on the famous cable car ride of Puerto
Plata - this ride is about 6-7 minutes and take you through some of the
most incredible scenery.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
While I was generally (and mostly) staying in resort areas, I did manage
to stay outside of the resort for a couple days. My good friend Davi was
nice enough to let me stay at his house for a couple days. Here's a look
at what I woke up too in the morning (while it was snowing at home!).

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;The
Pictures&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
Just before leaving - I took a picture of the new backpack. I had
recently sewn on patches of countries I had been too. My excitement was
building!

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
Punta Cana - one of the more artsy-fartsy types of pictures I grabbed. I
did this with my phone held close to the water and shooting the picture
with one hand. I thought it came out great.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][1]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
In Puerto Plata - a peculiar shot of the always freezing and infamous
bucket of water. This is what I used to take a shower.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][2]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
This is a shot of the side of Davi's house. I really liked how the
texture of the wall complimented the greenery around it. This is
probably my favorite picture.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][3]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
On the cable car - just as we were about to hit the tower. When you get
there, you feel a huge bump, a drop and all the 10 or so folks in the
car go "ohhhh"

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][4]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
This was a sign along the way to Puerto Plata (by bus).

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][5]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
As of this writing, 3 people have died from Cholera in the Dominican -
signs like this were on posts in public places and on the back of water
trucks.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][6]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
My wonderful companions for the baseball game in San Fransisco.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][7]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
A shot while working on a few things later in the day outside.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][8]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
So, there you have it.. some video, some pictures. All in all I thought
I took allot more photos/video than ever before. I look forward to the
next time!

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9o-1utRuI/AAAAAAAAA1E/3hs22LADnEE/s640/1293993234338.jpg" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9o-1utRuI/AAAAAAAAA1E/3hs22LADnEE/s1600/1293993234338.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TSIy3Nvs-tI/AAAAAAAAAv4/-PpA_7Aj8sw/s640/1294068486825.jpg" /&gt;]: http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TSIy3Nvs-tI/AAAAAAAAAv4/-PpA_7Aj8sw/s1600/1294068486825.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9oIA00xeI/AAAAAAAAAxs/65cVe3AnLk0/s640/IMG_0228.jpg" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9oIA00xeI/AAAAAAAAAxs/65cVe3AnLk0/s1600/IMG_0228.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9ocgDiJBI/AAAAAAAAAyw/XOHwzaAQa_Q/s640/IMG_0243.jpg" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9ocgDiJBI/AAAAAAAAAyw/XOHwzaAQa_Q/s1600/IMG_0243.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9ouVlvBhI/AAAAAAAAAz0/mNzqi0x7Hfw/s640/IMG_0279.jpg" /&gt;]: http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9ouVlvBhI/AAAAAAAAAz0/mNzqi0x7Hfw/s1600/IMG_0279.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9pOFkejaI/AAAAAAAAA2I/0b7ETDORQRc/s640/1294315758549.jpg" /&gt;]: http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9pOFkejaI/AAAAAAAAA2I/0b7ETDORQRc/s1600/1294315758549.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9pSqTbPaI/AAAAAAAAA2g/qjOEo0uczJk/s640/1294344802342.jpg" /&gt;]: http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9pSqTbPaI/AAAAAAAAA2g/qjOEo0uczJk/s1600/1294344802342.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9phEER4VI/AAAAAAAAA3g/rQVk8cDx4h8/s640/1294687325797.jpg" /&gt;]: http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9phEER4VI/AAAAAAAAA3g/rQVk8cDx4h8/s1600/1294687325797.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9ptJ7ANnI/AAAAAAAAA4U/elX3uXIOlyM/s640/1294783587773.jpg" /&gt;]: http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TT9ptJ7ANnI/AAAAAAAAA4U/elX3uXIOlyM/s1600/1294783587773.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Dominican"></category><category term="Travel"></category></entry><entry><title>The New, New Dominican in January 2011 - Part 2</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/the-new-new-dominican-in-january-2011-part-2/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-22T19:27:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-22:articles/the-new-new-dominican-in-january-2011-part-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="http://blogging-kevin.blogspot.com/2011/01/new-new-dominican-in-january-2011-part.html"&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; on the Dominican, I offered an explanation of that
special "thing" that gets me back there time and time again. That thing
is what as made me (some years) go back up to 4 times in a 12 month
period. That's more often than I've been to Vancouver, for those
counting. In this, the second part of the series, I'd like to share some
stories and anecdotes from this recent trip.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, on this trip I had some clear ideas about what I was going to do
differently (from other recent trips to the Dominican). One change I was
going to make was to take more pictures and video. I think you'll see in
the next post, that I did succeed in that respect. The sheer volume of
pictures and video I captured was staggering. Another plan I had before
leaving, was to integrate more into the local lifestyle more than I ever
have. To that end, let me explain how some these efforts unfolded.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Getting local voice and data service (prepaid) was one very important
plan I had. I spent some time online looking up the different phone
companies (Orange, Claro, Vivo) and their frequencies used and network
coverage. Since I'm using am HTC G2 - it was clear that Orange was the
network I would need to use. The process itself will be covered in
another post, but I wanted to share some of the fun that I encountered
while trying to get what I needed. The first step was getting voice
access at a mall.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I had arrived at the mall and found the Orange Shop - the man at
the counter seemed to speak English great. He was personal able and
seemed also to know exactly what I needed. Then, he said "I need your
passport". My jaw dropped and I said I didn't have it. He then says he
needed a passport to setup and account. Bizarre. This then began a
process of me running between the resort, the mall, and another small
range kiosk in a Super Mercado.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This little booth was closer to the resort, so it made sense not to go
all the way back to the mall - but when I got there it was busy. The
counter was filled with people, so I just stood behind the person who
seemed to look like he'd be the first to go. Not much was happening when
a person came up to the counter, said something in Spanish (that I
didn't understand), paid and left. I was a little taken aback here until
I realized that the concept of waiting in lines is kind of a foreign one
to many Dominicans. I immediately asserted myself up to the counter and
asked in English for "prepaid voice".  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, that didn't go so good. I got a blank look from that. I sure wish I
had taken a picture of his face. The next thing I attempted was to show
my phone and say "prepago". Well, this was enough for the fellow who
seemed to be squatting at the booth to my right to start speaking in
Spanish and then to me in English and he helped me communicate what I
was after to the person working in the small booth. That worked out,
despite him telling me about 18 times that my phone was still "locked".
That would be one of the many times on this trip I would wish for fluent
command of Spanish.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next experience with phone service was while waiting for a bus at the
terminal in Santo Domingo. I had about an hour free and there was
another Orange both just sitting in front of my (while I drink my bottle
of water). Since I didn't have data access an I had recently found out
how to hook this up, I decided I would give this a shot. I spoke to the
lady and said that I wanted "Prepaid data on a USB stick". I pointed at
a picture of it and we were off to the races. One passport and about $30
later, I was set to go. At some point she was trying to explain to me in
Spanish that this access to the Internet was only good for "ono dia".
Ok, 24 hours, that's cool. But, how much data am I able to use? That
question didn't work out so well. What happened next (after seeing she
had a computer) was a comical exchange using the Google Translate
website to translate text back and forth. Since Google didn't really get
the essence of what I was asking it took a few attempts to figure out
the best way to ask my question. Eventually, thanks to Google, I found
out that I would be allotted 1 GB of data for the day while in use.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of bussing from Punta Cana to Puerto Plata was another
somewhat comical process. The cabbie I had met in Punta Cana was great
and dropped me at the express bus to Santo Domingo, which was perfect.
Once we stopped in Santo Domingo at a fairly nondescript corner in the
city, I wasn't aware of this being where I would have to get off. The
bus driver came up to me and was screaming allot of Spanish words but
among them were the "Terminal". He was saying I had to get off. Since my
bag was already out, he directed me to another man who I thought was
going to show me where the Terminal was (I looked around and it was
nowhere to be seen). He went up to a person, grabbed keys and took me to
a car. I hopped in and we were off. I thought "Am I in a cab?" "Am I
going to have to pay for this trip?". After a few blocks, I saw the
large Grand Caribe terminal to the right. The man driving the car helped
me with my bags and let me go and I had nothing to pay.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting to Puerto Plata, my good friend Yanelis was at the bus top
waiting for me. We then went over to her house (via motorcycle) and I
visited everyone until Davi came by. With Davi, we went up to his house
in the mountain and I stayed there for a couple nights. What a
wonderful, refreshing experience. Despite being bitten by mosquitoes
like crazy (I didn't realize that's what the net was for), I was loving
it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I woke up in the morning, this is what I saw. Just incredible:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later, my travel companion Julio decided he wanted to rent a
car for 24 hours. The rental was going to cost $70 US cash (with
insurance). The great thing about this is that Julio wanted me to drive.
You may not be familiar with &lt;a href="http://dr1.com/living/road/3.shtml"&gt;the driving differences&lt;/a&gt; from Canada,
but many of the rules are different. I find it to be more of a
pleasurable experience to drive there because of how things are more
organic on the road. That was a fun day.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm told (by someone who speaks the language) that I have about 20%
command of speaking Spanish and about 40% recognition of the spoken
language. I have the sense that total immersion in a location with the
language is really the on way I'm going to take myself to the next level
and get to being fluent to a level of 40-50%. What are your thoughts
about learning another language?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Dominican"></category><category term="Travel"></category></entry><entry><title>The New, New Dominican in January 2011 - Part 1</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/the-new-new-dominican-in-january-2011-part-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T13:17:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/the-new-new-dominican-in-january-2011-part-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There some basic reasons why I go back to the Dominican time and time
again. Some of that is easy to describe (great weather, good-looking
people, beautiful scenery) - but it's the stuff that is increasingly
harder to describe that I'd like to take a look at in this first of many
part look at the Dominican in 2011. I have written &lt;a href="http://blogging-kevin.blogspot.com/search/label/Dominican"&gt;quite a bit&lt;/a&gt; about
the Dominican here, and I hope you join me in revisiting a locale that
is near-and dear to my heart.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This time around I was able to see more of this great country than I
have ever seen. I started in Punta Cana at a resort called the Majestic
Elegance and then was able to get to the "north coast" by bus. This
would be a north-west bound trip through Santo Domingo and around the
famed mountains of the north. On display during this trip was the
wonderful and scenic countryside that is often missed by those that
choose to say resort-bound. The small villages, the great people, the
makeshift stands offering various wares and the sugar cane fields (that
kind of reminded me of looking at corn). The beauty of all this is
breathtaking, and one I imagine the Dominican's take for granted.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, the beauty is still not that "thing" that draws me to this place.
It's enough, I'm sure, to draw anyone else what has had the opportunity
to be out here - but It's not what I'm trying to describe. And, as you
might imagine I met a number of folks, both inside and outside of the
resorts I was in. One such fellow was a very helpful cab driver named
Saidoo (I may have the spelling wrong there). His English was great and
very helpful as I enlisted in his help to get me (and my mobile phone)
connected to a local provider. My first interaction with him required
that he take me to a mall, then back to the resort (to get my passport)
and then to return again. The rides were a little pricey, but they wet
down in price as my necessity went up. I appreciated that. He was
incredibly helpful in getting me to the right bus for the start of my
journey and ended up being the man that could get anything I needed.
Saidoo was also very well versed in the bigger picture Dominican - he
was a pleasure to speak with.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still though, the helpfulness of everyday Dominicans is not that "thing"
I'm looking to get across. Something here is just so amazing. While in
Puerto Plata, a conversation with my good friend Davi lead to a
startling piece of information. The local "iglesia" or church in the
Barrio had not been paying it's bills. It was past -due on rent for a
staggering 9 months. The big question in my mind was - how the hell
would this place still be here after this long? Davi turns to me,
smiles, and says "They are too well-respected". I really didn't think I
could imagine a Canada or anywhere else with rules like these. Rules
that could be so easily broken because of the enormous respect you may
have in the community. Indeed, I have always known this was a place that
favored "Working things out naturally" as opposed to what is all to
common in Canada "legislatively working things out".  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and things get worked out roughly in many places too - it's not
always pretty, but the system seems to work and defy what we commonly
accept as Canadians. But, that still wasn't it. While still in the
Barrio, I met Giancarlo, the son of my good friend Martin. It was great
that he had noticed me from previous trips - though he spoke no English
and, frankly, my Spanish sucks. He seemed excited to show me his new
bicycle. I went around the corner to check it out and, wow, it was in
rough shape. The chain was rusted and bent in unusual ways, the center
shaft (for the pedals) was loose, jammed and made riding impossible, and
the bike had a flat on the back. Yet, still, Giancarlo was excited and
clearly wanted to see if I could help fix it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went over and did what I could - the chain was a challenge, but I took
my time to unravel it and get it onto the gears. Good, that was a start.
I asked Giancarlo to go after some tools and he came back with a huge
adjustable wrench - good enough - I can work with this. I loosened the
center nut and found a huge piece (possibly bearings) was missing. Not
good. I had another idea, why not tighten it as much as possible? I did
that and managed to improve the ride-ability of the bike. I then gave it
to Giancarlo and he looked as if I had given him Christmas present. He
went straight to the "tire guy" to get the back tube fixed and he was
riding that bike for the entire week (and getting flats) while I was
here.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the lesson, and that "thing" that is so hard to describe. I
could call it a certain positivity or appreciation for the things and
friends you have - but it's more. It's this outlook that Dominicans have
that is often described with a "Tranquillo", but to me is the essence of
what brings me back. Problems really do roll of their shoulders. They
appreciate the little things more and let go what they don't seem to
get. They work hard, as a group of people, more than any other people I
have ever met. We have so much to learn from other places, and I would
start by teaching Canada to live a little (or allot) more Dominican.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: red;"&gt;UPDATED&lt;/span&gt;:
Here's video of me working on Giancarlo's bycyle. You also see the
Iglesia at the start of the video.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Dominican"></category><category term="Travel"></category></entry><entry><title>Time to give thanks...</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/time-to-give-thanks/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:53:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/time-to-give-thanks/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: 13px;"&gt;There
are those that will TAKE from you - all they do is TAKE as much as they
can get. I want to Give Thanks to those that GIVE, give "real" love,
give time, give energy, give in, give it all they can for a better day -
even if they don't even know why. I thank all those (here, and passed
on) who have made my own, and other people's lives better.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: 13px;"&gt;  
&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;It's
not often in style to appreciate and thank those that may not be happily
in your life, or those that may have passed on. But, I say, this never
goes out of style. So, I say thanks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;  
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;-
Thank You, Mrs Walker for being such an amazing teacher and guidance
counselor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;-
Thank You, Father, you taught me many things - many things you don't
even know&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;-
Thank You, Mother, for showing me the other side wasn't so bad, giving
me a place to learn values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;-
Thank You, Crystal, Cara, and Jessica, for showing me that the story can
be a happy story&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;-
Thank You Sick Kids, for the miracle you performed - and all of your
miracles ([Donate!][])&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;

&lt;div style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: medium; margin: 0px;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;-
Thank You, Derek. Just for being you. The empty space without you will
never be replaced&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: medium; margin: 0px;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;-
Thank You, Friends, all of you know who you are. You have made me a
better person - even though we live far away, I'm glad we can be in
touch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;-
Thank You, person who let me take that lane on the highway yesterday -
you'll never know how much I needed that&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="color: white;"&gt;
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: 'lucida grande',tahoma,verdana,arial,sans-serif; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 13px;"&gt;..
And Thank You anyone else that should be, and will be on this
list.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Family"></category><category term="Thanks"></category></entry><entry><title>10 Best Movies of 2010</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/10-best-movies-of-2010/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/10-best-movies-of-2010/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][image]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the thing, I tend to watch a lot of movies. It may be because,
instead of watching TV, I end up watching movies? I'm really not sure
why I have always liked watching movies - and even seeing what it takes
to makes movies. It's all entertainment and escape at it's best. Each
year, I can say I've seen most of what's out there, though some movies
(often Oscar Bait-y types) escape my viewing pleasure.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, there were a number of great and cool movies that I thought
were the best. Some that probably deserve mention, but I haven't seen
are Black Swan, True Grit, Enter The Void, The Kids are All Right,
King's Speech, and Winter's Bone. For the rest, take a look at what I
thought were the best of this year.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][1]][1]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;10. Get Him To
The Greek&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1226229/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/offer-listing/B002ZG97PQ?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=am2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=330641&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B002ZG97PQ"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B002ZG97PQ" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
The best comedy this year has to be Russell Brand's return as rock star
Aldous Snow. It almost seems like he was meant to play this character.
Previusly, Brand played this character in another wonderful comedy,
Forgetting Sarah Marshall. I really loved the chemistry between Brand
and Jonah Hill and the cameos alone were funny as hell. P. Diddy was
great here too, who knew he could be funny?. It's mostly stupid and
gross comedy, but there is a serious side there too. This is precisely
the way I would envision the process of picking up a drugged out rock
star.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][3]][3]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;9. The Karate
Kid&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1155076/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B003WOUP2Y?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003WOUP2Y"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B003WOUP2Y" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
I was really not expecting to like this. The little I knew about it
(Kung Fu as the fighting style not Karate, relative unknown Jaden Smith,
Jackie Chan) - made me think this really was going to be trash. Boy, was
I surprised with what I saw! Smith did a great job of acting like a kid
with a lot to learn, Jackie Chan wasn't doing his regular jokey shtick
here either. The understated nature of nearly everything in this movie
makes it come out as a real winner - and wipes thoughts of original out
of your mind. The fact that it made a crap load of money probably
guarantees a sequel.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][7]][7]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;8.
Machete&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0985694/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B002ZG98CS?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B002ZG98CS"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B002ZG98CS" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
I love so much about this film that it's a wonder why it's not higher on
my list. Machete is the movie trailer that turned into an actual movie.
And that movie is amazing in ways that are unexplainable. Watching Trejo
finally getting a leading role and letting him rip shit up like he does.
Michelle Rodriguez looks incredible and plays a great hard-ass. If you
are a fan of the grind house style movie, this is your movie. And, even
thought it didn't make a lot of money it &lt;strong&gt;made&lt;/strong&gt;money. I hope to see
more of this.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][11]][11]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;7. Let Me
In&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1228987/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B003EYVXUU?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003EYVXUU"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B003EYVXUU" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
Let Me In was another of those surprise movies. When I heard that they
were remaking the AMAZING Swedish movie &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1139797/"&gt;Let the Right One In&lt;/a&gt;, I was
more than a bit cynical. This seemed too soon for this. What ended up on
screen was incredible for a movie that so many were not looking forward
too. Most of this rested on the shoulders of Chloe Moretz and I should
she did a great job of being strong and venerable all at the same time.
Richard Jenkins was great as the father. Do yourself a favor and see
both Let the Right One In and this movie.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][15]][15]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;6.
Buried&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1462758/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B003L20IFQ?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003L20IFQ"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B003L20IFQ" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
This movie is a testament to how much can be done with so little.
Essentially this is one man, a phone, dirt and a coffin. What Ryan
Reynolds does here is make me believe that he's in trouble and imminent
danger. The tension in the movie exists right to the last minute with
what I'll describe as an unexpected ended. I wasn't expect it, at least.
Rodrigo Cortés makes a wonderful, basic and thrilling story, work. As an
added bonus, most of the released posers were incredible leading up to
the film. This is one that I was looking forward to when I heard about
it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][19]][19]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;5. The Social
Network&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1285016/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B004AJDE8C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B004AJDE8C"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B004AJDE8C" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
Another surprise movie, but it really shouldn't have been a surprise.
Look at the talent behind this - director David Fincher and writer Aaron
Sorkin. What they made with this movie was more than the technical
details (which is often wrong in movies to begin with). They made a
movie about the beginnings of an idea - and made that movie at exactly a
time when Facebook was in the news. You have great performances by
Eisenberg and Timberlake and genuinely interesting characters.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][23]][23]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;4. Scott
Pilgrim vs The World&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0446029/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B00447850C?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00447850C"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B00447850C" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
The movie that practically every geek on the planet was waiting for,
finally arrived in 2010. And it was very good. For a movie about a guy
from Toronto, shot in Toronto this was a source of great pride to see
our wonderful city on display like this. Casa Loma never looked so good!
Well, it had me at Toronto. But, so much of everything else about this
movie is amazing. From the hyperactive action, to the performances by
Cera and Winstead to the sets to, well, everything else. A great movie.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][27]][27]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;3. Kick-Ass
&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1250777/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B003LSTWES?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003LSTWES"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B003LSTWES" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
2010 was definitely the year for Toronto as a location. In this movie,
Toronto was the location - but the in-movie city remained unknown.
Kick-Ass, of course, was the introduction to super heroes without any
super powers. A new kind of comic book movie. And, wow, does it Kick
Ass. All of the characters were interesting and flawed and the humor of
it all made me laugh a lot. Also Hit Girl is someone you never want to
meet in a dark alley.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][31]][31]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;2. The
Town&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0840361/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B0047Z94A6?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0047Z94A6"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B0047Z94A6" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
The one thing you'll be struck by with this second amazing directorial
effort by Ben Affleck, is the weight of emotion in all of the characters
here. Everyone in this movie is just excellent, from Ben Affleck to
Rebecca Hall to Jon Hamm to Jeremy Renner. This is a very character
driven movie about a small town in Boston and, frankly, the story just
blows you away. Not by how original the story is, but by HOW it's told.
I expect Affleck to get an Oscar or three for this one.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][35]][35]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;1.
Inception&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1375666/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B002ZG981E?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B002ZG981E"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B002ZG981E" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
Christopher Nolan is a movie-making genius. What he does with story,
sound and image is just incredible. Inception is on the top of most
people's lists this year because it is one thing - the best movie of
2010. The story is so multi-layered, so interesting, so visual - you'll
go back many times and still not fully understand what this all means. A
beautiful film in every regard. You'll also love how Nolan has made an
effort to use as much real and practical effects as possible - it shows
in the final product. I can't wait to see what he does next.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;Movies I
thought really sucked this year:&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;Shutter Island
&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1130884/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B003ITZBR2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003ITZBR2"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
This one is moody and well-made and incredibly actied by DiCaprio - but
I felt the story was stupid. Really, I saw was was coming a mile away
and there was really no suspense to it. You can make garbage look
pretty, but it's still garbage right?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;The Human
Centipede&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1467304/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B003L20IEM?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003L20IEM"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B003L20IEM" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
Really, what were they thinking? That's pretty much what was going
through my mind every minute of this film. I essentially felt like the
woman at the back of the line on this one. Force fed fecal matter of a
movie. Brutal.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;"&gt;The Book of
Eli&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1037705/"&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B003CN5S7M?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=390961&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003CN5S7M"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=B003CN5S7M" /&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
The book is a bible. Eli is blind. Really horrible movie.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. and probably many more that I can't think of. Better to bring in the
new year with positivity! Tell me what your favorite move(s) were this
year? Ho close is my list to your's? Did I miss anything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Movies"></category><category term="Review"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Project: Re-Finishing a Side Table</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/personal-project-re-finishing-a-side-table/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/personal-project-re-finishing-a-side-table/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you probably know, I'm a sucker for a new project or something cheap
and cool. This time around I needed to find an end table to sit on the
left of the couch in the living room. I was thinking this may hold a
lamp or perhaps just hold magazines or a nice looking chess set. You may
not know this, but Side Tables are damn &lt;a href="http://www.ikea.com/ca/en/catalog/products/20176282"&gt;expensive&lt;/a&gt; too. looking at
these things I was thinking (1) I don't want to pay a lot for the table
and (2) I want it to match the American Walnut stain of other tables in
the house - mainly because I suck at matching colors. With that, I went
out not specifically looking for a table, but keeping this in mind if I
came across it. And, boy, did I get what I was looking for!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][1]][1]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one fine October day I happened upon the Courtice Flea Market in a
small town just to the east of Oshawa. I had never been here previously,
but if I were to try and prepare you for this place - I would say it's
one big junk pile (I say that as affectionately as I possibly can). I
wasn't actually here to look for a table specifically - but I was
walking through an area with some interesting furniture piled up and
came across a small sturdy looking side table. The table certainly
didn't inspire much interest when I first saw it. The table had lots of
scratches and paint cracks. But, looking at it from afar, it was the
size I was looking for. I decided to get a closer look.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNoMD6cfYHI/AAAAAAAAAiY/g9XkbUmWsh0/s1600/SideTable-Start.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNoMD6cfYHI/AAAAAAAAAiY/g9XkbUmWsh0/s1600/SideTable-Start.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  The table when I brought it home&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you see in the above picture, those cracks and scratches were quite
plentiful. When I actually went up to the table and picked it up -
that's when I decided I wanted it. The weight of the table was quite
nice, and, I'm not a person who is able to determined the type of wood
by picking it up - but this wood really looked like something I could
work with. I decided to talk to the lady about buying the table.
&lt;strong&gt;Sticker Price: $15 - Price Paid: $10&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNs2xD19OiI/AAAAAAAAAic/_EM5SmPUd8g/s1600/SideTable.Apart.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNs2xD19OiI/AAAAAAAAAic/_EM5SmPUd8g/s1600/SideTable.Apart.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  The various parts of the table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty excited when I brought the table back - so much so that I
started to work on it right away.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-large;"&gt;#1 - Sand
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-large;"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-large;"&gt;
90 Grit sandpaper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After taking the table apart I used an orbital sander with 90 grit
sandpaper to get the old stain and finishing off the table. After the
first day, the table looked like this:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNs37zj7cWI/AAAAAAAAAig/7t4jE925DCc/s1600/SideTable.FirstDay.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNs37zj7cWI/AAAAAAAAAig/7t4jE925DCc/s1600/SideTable.FirstDay.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  After the first sanding, I wasn't completely finished&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was something unusual I found after the first day, the wood used
on the top level of the table seemed to be different from the wood used
on the middle level. Also, it appeared as though the legs were using the
same wood as the middle level. The wood on the table top was more of a
thin wood covering with possible particle board underneath - not good -
I was going to have to take care while sanding this level.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-large;"&gt;#2 - Sand
with 120 grit sandpaper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So, I was being rather touchy with the wood, but I managed to get the
first step done without any major damage. Also, learning from the &lt;a href="http://blog.cwl.cc/2010/06/personal-project-coffee-table-sanding.html"&gt;last
time&lt;/a&gt; I took on a table, I was very careful not to place any of the
sanded wood into or around water. This second stage of sanding went
quite smooth and quickly. The wood responded nicely to the 120 grit
paper as well. Also, I find that I tend to use half as much of the
higher grit sandpaper as I do of the lower grit.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNs8tWn4Y8I/AAAAAAAAAik/ruccpCaqxLc/s1600/SidelTable.Sanding+Done.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNs8tWn4Y8I/AAAAAAAAAik/ruccpCaqxLc/s1600/SidelTable.Sanding+Done.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  Sanding is finished&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-large;"&gt;#3 - Stain
the wood&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][6]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the wood sanded the way I wanted - I moved on to the staining
stage. In this case I decided to use a staining pad for all of this
process - including the legs. Given the small surface area that needed
stain, I wasn't going to need much for this at all. The stain I used
(shown at right) was Varathane, with the "American Walnut" color. I made
it a point to keep all of the tables I've stained so far at the same
color. I was fond of American Walnut when I first saw it on wood, so I
stayed with it. You'll also notice that the can of stain is small - this
&lt;strong&gt;$8.50&lt;/strong&gt; can of stain has so far been enough for me to stain a dining
room table, a coffee table and now a side table. Remarkable how much
this stain can cover. The key to staining woos seems to be the ability
to cover the surface in as uniform a way as you can possibly do. The
rest, will be dictated by how well you have sanded and the kind of wood
you have. I feel the better the wood, the better absorbed the stain is.
This is generally the most important stage of the process.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNs__Tgb3dI/AAAAAAAAAio/fyuWHwPLKQQ/s1600/SideTable.Stained.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNs__Tgb3dI/AAAAAAAAAio/fyuWHwPLKQQ/s1600/SideTable.Stained.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  The wood after just being stained. Notice how dull the surface is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-large;"&gt;#4 - Adding
the Finish&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
With this step, I also used a Varathane product for the finishing. For
all of my tables, I preferred to use a glossy finish, but you may decide
that gloss is a little too shiny. I have been pleased with the Varathane
product, so I'll keep using it. For this table, I decided early on that
three coats was going to be enough - if the table looked like it was
going to need more, I would add more. It turns out three coats was more
than enough. It's a good plan to (if you're not sure) stat with three
coats and add as you need too. In between coats you want to use a pad on
the wood surface to pop any bubbles and generally let the wood dry for
at leas 6-10 hours. The longest I left the wood before another coat was
a day.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNtBb9K8zrI/AAAAAAAAAis/BR3848ycByM/s1600/SideTable.Finishing.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNtBb9K8zrI/AAAAAAAAAis/BR3848ycByM/s1600/SideTable.Finishing.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  After the first coat of stain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-large;"&gt;#5 - The
final product&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The the stain done, and the table dry enough, I put it together. you are
really going to want to leave a good long time (maybe a week?) for the
finish to harden before actually using the wood. So, here are before and
after shots of the table's ultimate location:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNtCZsed-cI/AAAAAAAAAiw/2uVQsHSM2-0/s1600/SideTable.Before.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNtCZsed-cI/AAAAAAAAAiw/2uVQsHSM2-0/s1600/SideTable.Before.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  Before adding the table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNtCgh5m4wI/AAAAAAAAAi0/GzUVIaARBSY/s1600/SideTable.After.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNtCgh5m4wI/AAAAAAAAAi0/GzUVIaARBSY/s1600/SideTable.After.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  After adding the table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it! Any thoughts? I hope this series of blogs might have also
given you some ideas about changing up some stuff you have around the
house. As always, thoughts and questions are more than welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNtDsicFVPI/AAAAAAAAAi4/Q0xggiGBens/s200/SideTable.Thumb.jpg" /&gt;]: http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNtDsicFVPI/AAAAAAAAAi4/Q0xggiGBens/s1600/SideTable.Thumb.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNXnENyjh6I/AAAAAAAAASA/5YqIFmFbGMM/s200/Stain.jpg" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TNXnENyjh6I/AAAAAAAAASA/5YqIFmFbGMM/s1600/Stain.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Project"></category><category term="Refinsh"></category><category term="Wood"></category></entry><entry><title>Thoughts on Negativity</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/thoughts-on-negativity/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:42:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/thoughts-on-negativity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][image]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I read a nice little article on &lt;a href="http://www.pickthebrain.com/blog/negativity-a-motivation-killer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+pickthebrain/LYVv+%28PickTheBrain%29"&gt;Pick The Brain&lt;/a&gt; about the
idea that negativity can be a motivation killer. And another article
entitled &lt;a href="http://www.pickthebrain.com/blog/why-optimists-prosper/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+pickthebrain/LYVv+%28PickTheBrain%29"&gt;Why Optimists Prosper&lt;/a&gt;. I find myself in negative situations
all the time. My work can be a cauldron of negativity. Most of what I
generally do is about fixing problems - that's not a situation that
breeds allot of positivity. I too, succumb to negative thought
processes, and when I do, I usually pay for it. I usually snap out of
it, but the challenge has always been to be motivated from a positive
place towards a better future. I have been self employed now for more
than 10 years, a testament to a sort of positive motivation. I have come
across too many folks that, for some reason, are inherently negative and
I always hope to see that change for the better.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-edit.g?blogID=1463541672690543810&amp;amp;postID=5078298117425838461"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I'll give you an example, you must know folks like this. Your supposed
to meet your friend/lover/sibling/parent at a later time during the day,
but your still working. So tied up, in fact, that you can't get to the
phone as early as you would like. The day wears on and you finally get
the chance to call and you say that you have to work late and you can't
make it for your date/dinner/meeting/function. What's more, you say you
don't know when you'll be done. Well, the more positive of you would
probably say to themselves "OK, he/she's working late, no big deal. I
don't know the whole picture, but I'll find out more when he/she
returns". The negative thinker will instantly be thinking: "He's going
to be late, he's (done something wrong /cheating / hurt himself/ fallen
off a cliff / hit a moose)" and then that person would automatically
start to feel anxious, or in some cases cry or act out in horrible or
angry ways.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tends to be deeper than just flipping out over late appointments,
it's an instant and internal leaning towards the "worst in people"
instead of a positive thoughts. In our daily lives there are all sorts
of things that happen that are positive and negative. You might be
driving along and another driver cuts you off, you flip him the "bird"
and keep driving. Surely, that is a negative thing, but that is not what
I speak of when I talk about negativity. You may be in a conversation
and the person your talking to pisses you off, and in turn you go off on
them and give them a piece of your mind. That's also negative, but not
what I refer to here. These are all expressions of anger and annoyance,
a human emotion. Often anger can be used as a tool to motivate others
(or just as a release for us). Anger is a tool, it comes, goes and it
passes.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The negativity I speak of is sort of an internal trigger for people.
It's the sort of thing that keeps us from starting a businesses because
of fear, laziness or or lack of confidence. It's the sort of thing that
makes people use humor as a weapon to keep us from seeing their true
sadness (and perhaps them too). This may also what makes so many act out
in selfish or adversarial ways. The instantly negative thinker will
assume everyone is trying to take something from them. I think, in many
ways, this kind of thing is the underpinnings of what we might know as
depression - but I don't say I understand that. Actually, I don't
understand anything about the psychology of this, but, what I do
understand is the loss that comes from loosing loved ones that have
succumbed to this.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being overtaken by negativity holds us back in so many ways. It keeps us
from taking the time to understand other's points of view. It keeps us
from looking at or exploring the more important larger picture and
gaining a much-needed understanding. It keeps us from appreciating the
many wonderful things life has given us, often hiding under the surface.
When those that are in the throes negativity need to be motivated, it
does not seem to be possible from within. Struggling towards a common
goal is not possible because the struggle is stifling to them. I have
met a great many greatly motivated, intelligent, and beautiful people
who are held hostage by their own negativity. In many ways it cripples
them all that know them.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why do so many get trapped in this negative mental process? What can
be done to stem the tide of negativity? What if you're doing the things
I describe here?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this doesn't happen overnight, but being surrounded by those that
will support you is important. Being good to those that try to be there
for you - this is hard sometimes - but good things breed more good
things. I feel that, sometimes, forcing yourself to be patient also
helps. Even if the outcome or answers don't exist- just &lt;strong&gt;stop&lt;/strong&gt;and let
it happen. Let it sink in until you have more details and you might
simply free yourself from the negative shackles by waiting. Try to
separate yourself from those that bring negativity in your life. Also,
do this with negative influences like gossip or the news, if you can.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think? Am I way off the mark here? Is there a better word to
describe this than negativity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Negativity"></category></entry><entry><title>Book Review: Under the Dome</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/book-review-under-the-dome/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:41:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/book-review-under-the-dome/</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TFDMRTjtlYI/AAAAAAAABOo/Gw_zGihiMVw/s1600/200px-Under_the_Dome_Final.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TFDMRTjtlYI/AAAAAAAABOo/Gw_zGihiMVw/s1600/200px-Under_the_Dome_Final.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  From &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Under_the_Dome"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a techie, I am rarely presented the opportunity to read fiction
books. Yes, most of my reading tends to be news, current events and
articles or books related to the (sometimes dry) computer industry. When
I saw Stephen Kings UNDER THE DOME in hardcover hanging on the shelf of
my local Chapters, I was more than intrigued.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNDER THE DOME follows a number of townsfolk living in Chester's Mill,
Maine (King has a thing for Maine in his books). These seemingly normal
people are transformed in crazy and interesting ways as a domed force
field of some kind caps the small town completely. No one comes in, no
one leaves.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trapping of the towns people "like ants" is a perfect scenario for
King. His beautifully descriptive writing tells stories within even the
mundane of facts. He really gets into the "why" of what people do more
than any other fiction author I have read (admittedly, not many). Those
little tangents about what people are thinking at moments before or
after things happen are classic King moves.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than the descriptions too, the characters are very strong. The good
guy named Dale Barbara is a strong fellow I imagine as big, rough
looking. But with humility. The bad guy - Jim Rennie - is somewhat the
same, but with the look of perfect evil. I can already see who will play
these guys in a movie. I pick Ron Perlman for Barbara and Deniro for
Rennie. Perfect. I can't quite place Junior, but I would have bet that
someone like Heath Ledger could make that part great.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stakes are high too. You might not think so, but the kind of crazy
shit that can go down in a small town is really endless. When that movie
is made, it will need some really cool special effects. Also, I expect
this to be 'Hard R' - any less would be a disservice to the amazingly
described gore and horrible acts in the story.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gore is not all - I'm fascinated by the technology surrounding the
dome. I wont give away too much about what (or who) creates the dome;
but the tech behind the 15 minute pulses, the small holes in the
exterior of the dome and the level of transparency. King doesn't delve
into this nearly as much as I would liked. I wanted to know more.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't give you any more about the story either - you have to read the
close to 1100 pages yourself. I think if you take the ride, you'll be
happy you did.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a note: it took me seven damn months to read this book. Seven
months! You can grab the book here from Amazon.ca: &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/1439196966?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=facebook079-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=15121&amp;amp;creative=330641&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1439196966"&gt;Under the
Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.ca/e/ir?t=facebook079-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=15&amp;amp;a=1439196966" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Book"></category><category term="Review"></category></entry><entry><title>Personal Project: Coffee Table - Sanding, Staining, Varnishing</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/personal-project-coffee-table-sanding-staining-varnishing/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:40:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/personal-project-coffee-table-sanding-staining-varnishing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][image]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the recent months I have taken on a number of projects to improve
the look this house. In this case, I found a small wooden coffee table
at a Value Village for $19.99 and I saw potential in it. I could
visualize the look of it finished, even as it sit in the furniture
section of Value Village. The table as I bought it was not stained at
all - it had a number of large gashes on the top of it and the varnish
had a somewhat off-color to it. The great thing about this table
(besides the price) was how sturdy it appeared to be built. Nothing
screams "project" like some basic solid wood. I'm going to show you how
to take a coffee table, stain it and make it look great. This can be
done for easily less than $30 ($70, if you can't borrow a sander).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOCi860tPI/AAAAAAAABFo/SacID75f29Q/s320/OrgStain.jpg" /&gt;][]
  Coffee Table: The original look of the table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sanding is usually the most important part of the project. You want
to make sure you get the previous varnish off the wood and yet don't
want to take too much of the wood with it. To start with, I used an
orbital sander with the (Velcro sanding sheets). These are generally
about $40 at a hardware store. I started with 60 grit sandpaper. As I
was sanding I decided I wanted to stain as much of the table as possible
- so I took it apart into pieces. The roof of my truck was quite useful
for doing some of this work from waist-level. Here's a look a piece of
the table and the sander I was using:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][2]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sanding everything with the 60 grit sandpaper, I moved on to the
120 grit sandpaper to smooth out the rough surfaces. Usually just two
passes of sandpaper is enough, even though some will tell you that you
need to do a third (possibly with 180 grit). With this finished, I was
happy with the sanding stage.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanding Tip&lt;/strong&gt;: Sand in the direction of the grain of the wood. Also, I
was doing all this outside of my garage to keep from getting dust all
over - when sanding, be sure to wear a mask!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOFoGFGJSI/AAAAAAAABF0/VZO9yNQtzI0/s320/Stain.jpg" /&gt;][]
  The small bottle of stain used&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the sanding was finished, I started to stain. I used &lt;a href="http://www.homedepot.ca/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/CatalogSearchResultView?D=980260&amp;amp;Ntt=980260&amp;amp;catalogId=10051&amp;amp;langId=-15&amp;amp;storeId=10051&amp;amp;Dx=mode+matchallpartial&amp;amp;Ntx=mode+matchall&amp;amp;N=0&amp;amp;Ntk=P_PartNumber"&gt;Varathane
Professional Premium Wood Stain - American Walnut&lt;/a&gt; (236ml) - for this
job. As you can see by the size of the can, very little stain is
required. This can was half-empty when I started and still has some
stain left - you will not use much of this stuff. I used a natural
paintbrush and simply started to stain (continuing to stay with the
grain).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staining Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; It's sloppy and tends to really show later if you make
mistakes. I only placed one coat of the stain on the wood - but after
the first coat I took the time to touch up some of the spots that I
missed on the wood. be consistent and even whenever possible.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After letting the stain dry for a week ( yea, I gave it extra time), I
came back to start the lacquer stage. The varnish is used to protect the
wood and stain and create the finish of the table. For this process I
used and for this I used &lt;a href="http://rona.ca/shop/%7Evarnish-varathane-professional-varnish-flecto-219853_%21varathane_shop"&gt;Varathane - Professional Clear Finish (Oil
Int. Clear Gloss)&lt;/a&gt; (946ml). The gloss is great for table tops because
it really gives it that bit of shine you notice in a room. For this
project I will put three coats on the wood letting it dry about 6 hours
in-between coats. You'll use quite a bit more of the varnish than you
will the stain, so you want to pickup a larger can - I used the 946ml
size (roughly a liter).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOITqLFlDI/AAAAAAAABF4/BPpziQqRVeY/s320/Varnish.jpg" /&gt;][]
  The varnish used - note the "Clear Gloss" - this is shiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Varnishing Tips:&lt;/strong&gt; (a) give the previous coat time to dry, I gave it
at least 6 hours. I didn't put new varnish on if the surface was still
tacky (b) making sure you paint it all on evenly. This is a challenge
with glossy varnish since it hard to tell where you last painted and (c)
making sure that you do a light sanding or use a scrub pad on the
previous coating of varnish . This takes away the air bubbles and makes
the next coat smoother. In my case three coats was enough.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One warning, during all of this, water is your enemy. You have to use
varsol to clean the brushes (not water). You have to make sure the raw
wood does NOT come in contact with water or it will stain. I
accidentally rested one of the legs in water (just after sanding) and
here's what that did to the leg. Notice how prominent the stain is:   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][5]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the project is finished, the varnish on the table has hardened and
I have to say - I'm very happy with it. This is a definite improvement
over my previous table sanding project. I think I'm learning more every
time I take on one of these. Here are a few more pictures of the final,
stained table. Click through for larger versions.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][6]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][7]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][8]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd love to hear more about your own projects. What did you think of
this? Do you have any staining tips of your own to share?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOCi860tPI/AAAAAAAABFo/SacID75f29Q/s320/OrgStain.jpg" /&gt;]: http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOCi860tPI/AAAAAAAABFo/SacID75f29Q/s1600/OrgStain.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCODxqpe5aI/AAAAAAAABFw/wN7_s470DfY/s400/CoffeeTableApart.jpg" /&gt;]: http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCODxqpe5aI/AAAAAAAABFw/wN7_s470DfY/s1600/CoffeeTableApart.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOFoGFGJSI/AAAAAAAABF0/VZO9yNQtzI0/s320/Stain.jpg" /&gt;]: http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOFoGFGJSI/AAAAAAAABF0/VZO9yNQtzI0/s1600/Stain.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOITqLFlDI/AAAAAAAABF4/BPpziQqRVeY/s320/Varnish.jpg" /&gt;]: http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOITqLFlDI/AAAAAAAABF4/BPpziQqRVeY/s1600/Varnish.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOJqnyR5ZI/AAAAAAAABF8/OdsjiNlPdMc/s640/CoffeeTableLegDamage.jpg" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOJqnyR5ZI/AAAAAAAABF8/OdsjiNlPdMc/s1600/CoffeeTableLegDamage.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOKTU-jPiI/AAAAAAAABGA/rEOJL15QKxo/s400/1.jpg" /&gt;]: http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOKTU-jPiI/AAAAAAAABGA/rEOJL15QKxo/s1600/1.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOKdn7COxI/AAAAAAAABGE/vx4c-vPkjL4/s400/2.jpg" /&gt;]: http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOKdn7COxI/AAAAAAAABGE/vx4c-vPkjL4/s1600/2.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOKvva9ieI/AAAAAAAABGI/RXFKVGkn4Jw/s400/3.jpg" /&gt;]: http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TCOKvva9ieI/AAAAAAAABGI/RXFKVGkn4Jw/s1600/3.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Project"></category><category term="Refinsh"></category><category term="Wood"></category></entry><entry><title>Why I've always been a fan of Magnum P.I.</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/why-ive-always-been-a-fan-of-magnum-pi/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:40:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/why-ive-always-been-a-fan-of-magnum-pi/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of a very few personal posts you'll see me write here. The
regular fare on this blog is usually a mix of computer, technical stuff
with the occasional outrage over something with a dash of vacation
stories added. After spending a little time over the last few days (re)
watching the 8th (and final) season of Magnum PI, I thought I would stop
and reflect on what that show has meant to me over the years. It's
almost corny now that I'm 36 years old that I would have identified with
a television character so much.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To understand this, you really have to have a sense of timeline. Magnum
PI was in it's first run on TV from 1981 to 1988, this would have placed
the show on CBS in the rage of years for me from when I was 8 years old
to just about the middle of my 14th year. I was a kid in every sense of
the word when this show was running. Magnum PI was also a very popular
show - one of the higher rated shows for it's time. If they wanted too,
the producers of the show could have kept it going for some time after
it ended. But, in the spring of 1988, the show ended.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][1]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know what you're thinking, and your wrong. This show turned out to be
more than a show for me in a number of ways that go beyond some
pipsqueak kid watching the boob-tube. This is the unusual story behind
this show and it's effect on me when I was so young and it's apparent
effect on me now. As it turns out I'm in the middle of the years that
the Thomas Magnum character played out on the show (33 to 41). In many
ways its interesting, and sometimes scary to see this show with fresh
eyes as an older and (somewhat) wiser person - seeing things that the
kid could never have seen. I've also only seen the last season, none of
the 7 seasons that preceded it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many coincidences that have happened in my life that have
linked me to the Magnum PI character. perhaps as a child, I just needed
a character to identifiably with - something akin to GI Joe for a
generation before me. But, there always seemed to be more.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1984, as an 11 year old, my father decided to take me and my sister
to a baseball game. Since we lived in Sarnia at the time, it would ave
been difficult or impossible to get to Toronto to see a Blue Jays game.
We, instead ended up going to Detroit to catch a game at the Tiger
Stadium, watching a team that was on a serious tear that year and one
that would go on to win the World Series. This essentially became my
favorite baseball team as I followed the Tigers more and more as I got
older. I don't recall seeing the Magnum PI show at the time, but to see
that he was a big Tigers fan was really cool!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was the season when I finally started to watch Magnum PI in
first-run episodes. This being the last season, I was surprised to find
that in the final episode - they would use allot of Otis Redding's
music. I had heard allot of music from Otis Redding after seeing some
John Hughes movies years before and had become a huge fan of soul music,
and Otis Redding. I remember in the mid-80's, working in downtown
Toronto and after hearing Otis Redding for the first time - I wanted
that music! I remember walking up and down Young St searching through
all those classic record stores just to find any of his stuff. To hear
that music in the final episodes was an amazing coincidence, and kept me
watching.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][2]][2]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were other things, that naturally as a kid, I would end up
emulating at the time. I remember walking around with a Detroit Tigers
baseball hat quite a bit - but I also remember at the time thinking "am
I wearing this because I'm a fan of the Tigers or because I'm a fan of
Magnum PI?". I guess it wasn't much of a big deal, but in the mind of a
young boy with no identity to speak of, it mattered to me. Seeing stuf
like the logo on Magnum's shirt as he would kayak - it was of a man's
head and the number of 14. Naturally I would find this interesting
because my own birthday was June 14th.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of my younger years were a bit crazy, and having an escape like
Magnum PI actually helped me enormously. I found myself enjoying the
friendships between all of the main characters - Magnum, Rick , T.C.,
Higgins and the two dogs, Zeus and Apollo. The chemistry between all of
the actors was amazing - something we rarely see in today's polished
CSI'esque shows. As I would start watching the show more, I would see
allot of the re-runs as they were aired in syndication - but I never
managed to get to see the real narrative of the show as it was released.
In fact, not only have I not seen all of the 162 Magnum PI episodes, I
haven't really sen many of them in sequence either.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I get some of the in-jokes of the show (if you want to call them
jokes). I know that, for example, the number of 162 episodes was not a
random number - it's actually the number of games in a Major League
Baseball season. When I watch the show more these days, there are others
that I see too. It's amazing what you see, even after the years have
passed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][3]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the show is entirely out on DVD (Seasons &lt;a href="http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/dvd/Magnum-P-I-S1-Ff-Tom-Selleck-Roger-Young/025192471124-item.html?ref=Search+DVD:+%2527Tom+Selleck%2527"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/dvd/Magnum-Pi-S2-Ff-Tom-Selleck-Roger-Young/025192710322-item.html?ref=DVD:+CWBAB+Hero"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/dvd/Magnum-I-S3-Comp-Ff-Tom-Selleck-Roger-Young/025192922527-item.html?ref=DVD:+CWBAB+Link"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/dvd/Magnum-I-S4-Comp-Ff-Tom-Selleck/025192930027-item.html?ref=DVD:+CWBAB+Link"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/dvd/Magnum-I-S5-Comp-Ff-Tom-Selleck/025193050427-item.html?ref=DVD:+CWBAB+Link"&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/dvd/Magnum-I-S6-Comp-Ff-Selleck-Hillerman-Mosley-Manetti/025193057327-item.html?ref=DVD:+CWBAB+Link"&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/dvd/Magnum-I-S7-Comp-Ff-Selleck-Hillerman-Mosley-Manetti/025195005463-item.html?ref=DVD:+CWBAB+Link"&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/dvd/Magnum-I-S8-Comp-Ff-Selleck-Hillerman-Mosley-Manetti/025195016964-item.html?ref=DVD:+CWBAB+Link"&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;) I suggest you go check
them out, or at the very least buy me one of them. I have always
wondered how many other Magnum PI fans there are out there besides
myself. I did once come across a customer how had a model of the same
Ferrari that was used in the series too. Behind the model was a picture
of him sitting in a Ferrari in a setting that looked like Hawaii.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the next step for me as a fan of the show. I would like to
finally get up and go check out the location where all of this was
filmed. I want to finally make the pilgrimage to all the various
locations to check out what it's like down there. After all of these
years, I have no doubt that everyone there has forgotten about this 80's
TV show, but I certainly haven't forgotten. I look forward to digging up
more episodes and checking them out. If you're a fan too, I'd love to
hear about why you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TAVD1BmJTgI/AAAAAAAABD4/ZdMiq3qXC6s/s200/1_1_s_full.jpg" /&gt;]: http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TAVD1BmJTgI/AAAAAAAABD4/ZdMiq3qXC6s/s1600/1_1_s_full.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TAVVovoMLrI/AAAAAAAABEA/UqQnDgOj_K4/s320/8_13_b_full.jpg" /&gt;]: http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TAVVovoMLrI/AAAAAAAABEA/UqQnDgOj_K4/s1600/8_13_b_full.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TAVWAmQZxTI/AAAAAAAABEE/qVsQMpoHHx4/s320/8_5_k_full.jpg" /&gt;]: http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/TAVWAmQZxTI/AAAAAAAABEE/qVsQMpoHHx4/s1600/8_5_k_full.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Magnum"></category><category term="TV"></category></entry><entry><title>Speeding in Toronto? Be careful, watch out for ignorance!</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/speeding-in-toronto-be-careful-watch-out-for-ignorance/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:39:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/speeding-in-toronto-be-careful-watch-out-for-ignorance/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, it's those unrealistic cops and other ignorant folks you need to
worry about in Toronto and outskirts. Today, I had a basic exchange with
one such member of the police about speeding on Twitter. The officer,
Tim Burrows, who Tweets as &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/TrafficServices"&gt;@trafficservices&lt;/a&gt; had the following
exchange with me:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Now, I need to qualify all of this. Car crashes are dangerous no
matter how fast you go. I have been in a number of them myself as a
driver, passenger and a pedestrian. Always be safe when driving and
*always* drive according to your better judgement (the may not always
be what's posted on a sign).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the thing, we should all be ashamed of the system we drive in.
The process of catching speeders and other traffic rule breakers is
clearly nothing more than a cash grab, or possibly a tax on us. Let's be
clear, traffic collisions can be scary and dangerous, but most of the
rules we have to follow on the road have nothing to do with safety.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His basic points were three things (1) speed traps are in plain sight
(2) speeding tickets are revenue neutral and (3) rules are all about
safety. Let's look at these ideas, because you should at least be more
informed than the officer on what we face on a daily basis. Don't drink
his Kool Aid.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's look at this, point by point.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Speed Traps are in "plain sight"&lt;/strong&gt; - There are a number of examples
of this being just plain false. The cops in Toronto don't want you to
see them as you approach because you'll slow down, so they resort to a
number of tactics to hide themselves. As a deterrent to speeding, this
is useless, because if no one sees the cop, they are reminded of
nothing, much less that they should slow down. Here are a number of
examples:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][1]][1]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found on a blog named &lt;a href="http://spacingtoronto.ca/2008/01/29/are-speed-traps-the-best-us-of-police-resources/"&gt;Spacing Toronto&lt;/a&gt;, the picture is small, but you
can clearly see that the Police have done what they can to hide
themselves behind the trees. If not for the speeder they stopped, you
would not have seen these guys on approach. Another spot I'm very
familiar with is the corner of Gerrard St E and Blackburn St. This is a
common hidden location for the police to hide and catch those coming off
the bridge covering the Don Valley Parkway. It looks like this (source:
Google Maps):  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][2]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can probably tell what they hide behind in the summer months, yes,
the trees, the sloping pavement and the fence all create this perfect
way of tricking people into thinking nothing is there. Another common
trick I have seen used is the lone cop standing on a bridge pointing his
speed gun down on the highway below. Once they catch someone, they call
ahead and get a cruiser to stop you. Plain Sight? If you are lucky
enough to catch the cops in the act of hiding a speed trap, I would love
to see the pictures. We have to prove this major fallacy wrong.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Speed Traps/Tickets are Revenue Neutral after all costs factored&lt;/strong&gt;
- this is one big example of a fuzzy accounting process. The process
where they count up all the costs to ONLY the parties you deem important
and then leave all the rest out. The costs to those drivers who are
fined at these incredibly high rates are not revenue neutral at all. To
most, the high cost of the ticket is just the beginning. There is the
social stigma attached to being a speeder (more on that later), the high
cost of taking time off work and/or hiring legal representation, and the
insanely high cost of the insurance if you were to be convicted of one
of these charges. In some cases it gets even worse, you may in some
situations have your license suspended (without notification) and/or
face demerit points. Add all this up, and you have an incredible loss of
the little spending money a person takes home after tax - even for the
most minor of speeding charges!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the number of paralegal companies that exist in Toronto, my
&lt;a href="http://maps.google.ca/maps?hl=en&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;q=paralegal+toronto&amp;amp;fb=1&amp;amp;gl=ca&amp;amp;hq=paralegal&amp;amp;hnear=Toronto,+ON&amp;amp;view=text&amp;amp;ei=OqX-S9-UF4H48AaHw5D0DQ&amp;amp;ved=0CEgQtQMwAA&amp;amp;z=12"&gt;search&lt;/a&gt; on Google yielded 1,333 results! The hide-and-catch speeders
game not only pads the pocketbooks of the Police, it has created an
entire market for legal services. Not to mention that many of these
paralegal companies prey on the more uninformed folks who are clearly
intimidated by the cumbersome legal system we have. That's a post for
another day.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. It's all about safety&lt;/strong&gt; - This is one of the biggest lies that the
cops will ever feed you. They are not hiding behind the trees with radar
guns to keep us safe (revenue generation). They are not trying to create
the "speeding is criminal" stigma to create a safer road environment
(public support, fear). They don't over-legislate rules like the "racing
law" that get's your license suspended, gets you fined up to $10,000 and
your car towed immediately - because they want safer roads (all of the
above). &lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: red;"&gt;None
&lt;/span&gt;of the current speed enforcement policies or budget goes to
safety.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What, then, would the Police and Government be doing about all of the
above if they were actually trying to curb collisions and keep us safer?
I'm glad you asked, that is the most important question here. We need to
collectively stop these jokers from screwing us over. I personally don't
trust them with tax money as they stay "revenue neutral". Here's what we
need to go in the right direction:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roundabouts&lt;/strong&gt;- Many studies have concluded that roundabouts on our
roads reduce collisions. A Washington-based study concluded the
following about roundabouts:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more than 90% reduction in fatalities  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;80% reduction in injuries  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40% reduction in total number of crashes  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: small;"&gt;Source: "Safety
Effect of Roundabout Conversions in the United States: Empirical Bayes
Observational Before-After Study." Transportation Research Record No.
1751,
&lt;/span&gt;[&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: small;"&gt;Transportation
Research Board
(TRB)&lt;/span&gt;][]&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: small;"&gt;,
National Academy of Sciences (NAS), Washington, D.C. 2001&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even an article in &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/world/united-states/displaystory.cfm?story_id=9621685"&gt;The Economist&lt;/a&gt; (subscription required). talks
about the benefits of roundabouts. Provinces like Alberta are starting
to install them - &lt;a href="http://www.transportation.alberta.ca/roundabouts.wmv"&gt;here's&lt;/a&gt; what one looks like. But here in Toronto,
little or nothing but talk. And, how many roundabouts do we have in
Toronto? I'm sure you can count the number with your fingers. How much
of that "revenue" could be spent on roundabouts for safety instead of
more radar or laser guns?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed Limits&lt;/strong&gt; - Did you know that the 401's speed limit was actually
112km/hour in 1976 before it was dropped to the current 100/km an hour
(&lt;a href="http://www.roadscholar.on.ca/lateststory.html"&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). Did you also know that the minimum design speed of the 401
is apparently 130km/hour? Speed Limits need to be adjusted to be
appropriate to the area they are in. In the case of the above Gerrard St
E speed trap, the road itself is usually heavy up to River St. when you
arrive at the DVP Overpass, and then the road opens up. Those drivers
who enjoy this brief relief of traffic and go faster than the posted
40km/hr speed, are however, clipped immediately by the cash hungry cops.
The speed limits on the roads need to reflect real world conditions, and
not just set (and used) by the police for their advantage. Many other
locations probably deserve lower speed limits, but the majority of the
roads in Toronto have speed limits set WAY too low.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key statistic about speed, though is really not that "high speed
kills" as they would have you believe. It is actually the deviation from
the normal speed you are travelling on. Yes, that means Grama driving at
40+km/hr lower than others on the 401 will be MORE of a risk than
someone driving 40+km over the normal speed. Here's a graph to
illustrate that (&lt;a href="http://www.tfhrc.gov/safety/speed/speed.htm"&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;) :  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][4]][4]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed "stigma" and this the push to make those that might speed look
like criminals - needs to stop. The cops need to stop wasting our money
on hiding in bushes trying to catch speeders and put that money in more
useful endeavors (like building roundabouts, catching actual bad guys,
perhaps?). Everyone needs to call or email their local politician and
tell them that the current policies are unacceptable. When you hear a
cop talk stupidness about speeding policies - correct them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S_6cTw69yoI/AAAAAAAABDY/uaCDmlZ8-Io/s640/TweetExchange.png" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S_6cTw69yoI/AAAAAAAABDY/uaCDmlZ8-Io/s1600/TweetExchange.png
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S_6gzL0YixI/AAAAAAAABDc/b4EyItcX4bA/s400/SpeedTrap.png" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S_6gzL0YixI/AAAAAAAABDc/b4EyItcX4bA/s1600/SpeedTrap.png
  [&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: small;"&gt;Transportation
  Research Board (TRB)&lt;/span&gt;]: http://pubsindex.trb.org/document/view/default.asp?lbid=694939&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Police"></category><category term="Speeding"></category><category term="Traffic"></category><category term="Twitter"></category></entry><entry><title>My Niece's 2010 Spring Concert footage</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/my-nieces-2010-spring-concert-footage/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:37:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/my-nieces-2010-spring-concert-footage/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time my nieces Cara and Jessica are in a concert at their school,
&lt;a href="http://esip.edu.gov.on.ca/english/profiles/school_info.asp?ID=B66060&amp;amp;schoolid=244791"&gt;Harmony Heights Public School&lt;/a&gt;, I try to attend and gather some
useful pictures and video. Most of the time I fail - my camera just
doesn't cut it. I'm in the market for a decent HD camera, but for now
we're stuck with this. I should also note that I'm not exactly in the
best position to get this either - I should probably have been in the
area where the gawker parents go to get footage, maybe next time :)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, without further delay - here is what I have gathered for all to
enjoy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up is Cara on the recorder - she is going to be the third from
left on back row. Here's a picture of all the kids playing:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][1]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to see and hear what they sound like, check out this
blurry video:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is Jessica, she was actually involved in a couple songs in this
concert. She sang "My Favorite Things" and "The Hockey Song". Here's a
shot of the kids about to sing - Jessica is the first from the left on
the bottom row:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][2]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to hear them, take a look at the video:&lt;br /&gt;
"My Favorite Things"  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Hockey Song"  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There you have it... enjoy the videos and let me know if you like them.
I look forward to making more (and in better quality).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S-Bwug32iSI/AAAAAAAAA-s/FVAiEpmFyGU/s200/Kids.jpg" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S-Bwug32iSI/AAAAAAAAA-s/FVAiEpmFyGU/s1600/Kids.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S-BxtiVfKUI/AAAAAAAAA-w/QmqqjKDBmiU/s400/Cara+Recorder.jpg" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S-BxtiVfKUI/AAAAAAAAA-w/QmqqjKDBmiU/s1600/Cara+Recorder.jpg
  [&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S-BydS_9hDI/AAAAAAAAA-0/N8Gu-iR22DY/s400/Jessica-Sing.jpg" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_gsOoH9Cd_Q0/S-BydS_9hDI/AAAAAAAAA-0/N8Gu-iR22DY/s1600/Jessica-Sing.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Family"></category><category term="Music"></category></entry><entry><title>Roger Ebert - Movie Critic, and wise man</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/roger-ebert-movie-critic-and-wise-man/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:36:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/roger-ebert-movie-critic-and-wise-man/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I was reading a fascinating Esquire &lt;a href="http://www.esquire.com/print-this/roger-ebert-0310"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about none other
than Roger Ebert - I had seen him on TV years ago when he was on Siskel
and Ebert. More after the jump...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-create.g?blogID=4704524484401992917"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You might remember the how that show was - they review Pulp Fiction here
(Ebert is the one on the right):&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roger, facing his own mortality, goes on to say this:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I believe that if, at the end of it all, according to our abilities, we
have done something to make others a little happier, and something to
make ourselves a little happier, that is about the best we can do. To
make others less happy is a crime. To make ourselves unhappy is where
all crime starts. We must try to contribute joy to the world. That is
true no matter what our problems, our health, our circumstances. We must
try. I didn't always know this, and am happy I lived long enough to find
it out."  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, thank you Roger for the wise words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Ebert"></category><category term="Movies"></category></entry><entry><title>My cousin Laddie's Obit...</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/my-cousin-laddies-obit/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:35:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/my-cousin-laddies-obit/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was posted in the Toronto Sun on November 12, 2008:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BARNSWELL, Christopher “Laddie” McGregor -It is with great sadness that
the family of Christopher Barnswell announce his passing on Nov. 8th,
2008. Born Mar. 13th, 1980, he was the cherished son of Nancy and Ted
Petitpas and Collin Barnswell. Beloved brother of Corby Costain, Nikita
Barnswell and Keisha Barnswell. He will be greatly missed by his
grandparents, aunts, uncles, cousins, nieces, and nephews, all of whom
he treasured dearly. He will be remembered for his kindness, sincerity,
and heart of gold. Although Chris has passed, his loved ones know that
he has found peace in his heart, and will cherish their memories of him
always.Visitation will be held on Fri., Nov. 14th from 4-7:00p.m. A
service will take place on Sat., Nov. 15th at 3:00p.m. Both will be held
at the Trull Funeral Home and Cremation Centre, 1111 Danforth Ave.,
Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Family"></category></entry><entry><title>White Cowbell - Horseshoe Tavern - March 8, 2008</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/white-cowbell-horseshoe-tavern-march-8-2008/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:33:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/white-cowbell-horseshoe-tavern-march-8-2008/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My lord, it just so happens we push an all-time snowfall record on the
day the Cowbell come home. I was not going to let a little thing like
snow get in my way! I did not get to see last night's show in Hamilton -
and I missed all of the western tour.. So I was more than a little
bummed...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get there after two hours of driving, already everyone but my sister
had dropped out of the night's proceedings, and to make matters worse -
I have to wait in some sort of lineup? I thought "What is this? Do they
not know who I am?". Well, they didn't, and I waited about 30mins to get
in, the lads had already finished the opening and a song.. I was so glad
to be back inside the Casa Cowbell for the first time this year!   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a packed house! The fans were pumped! it also appeared to be a
ticket with 7 other bands (as one of the very friendly bouncers would
explain). I was so much more in tune with things here than the last
time. The Jager girls were occasionally circulating around the stage
refreshing the front-row devotees, I was stuck a few rows back
double-fisting a couple Stella's...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bubba would do an uncharacteristically perfect rendition of "Tear You a
New One" - practice! The dancing girl looked great, she's lost weight,
but Sgt Rock seems to have gained facial hair - that makes them even?
You tell me. "Put The South In Your Mouth" gets interactive and then the
boys are whisked off... Seriously, I must have gotten whiplash with how
fast they spit!   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did get to say hi at various moment, I had to let Charles and the
others know I had attended and then I was off myself. The very friendly
and drunk lady I met at the stage was all too happy to share the she'd
be married in a few days. Congratulations to you!!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a short one, yes - but it was sweet to see the WCO again and I
look forward to this year's adventures!! What's next?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Music"></category><category term="White Cowbell Oaklahoma"></category></entry><entry><title>Panama Backpacker Style - 6</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/panama-backpacker-style-6/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:31:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/panama-backpacker-style-6/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 13 - Penonomé&lt;br /&gt;
Waking up this morning the distinct sound of partying outside was really
cool. I was told that this Carnival goes four days - all day, all night
- and doesn't stop. I decided to walk towards the sounds, I had to
remember where I was.. No street signs here to help. Gathering some
landmarks I work backwards with these:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MUSEO HNOS ARIAS MADRID, turn left  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corp. el sol, turn right&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get to see the local Internet cafe - where the access is slow and they
charge .60c an hour, by far the cheapest access in town. The one thing
that is super annoying though, is that they filtered suspect "Porn"
sites. I would be in Facebook and click on a friend's profile and a
filtering message comes up and KILLS the web browser and all the tabs I
have open! Brutal to say the least. That is good enough amusement for a
couple hours, I then grab lunch at Pio Pio, and head back towards all
the action in town. What action indeed! On the main street in town there
are about 8 tanker trucks lined up and down road - the sole purpose of
these being to spray water on the people below dancing in the sun. It
was great, I went in and got wet and sprayed myself, I even got the
chance to hop on top of a tanker and spray the people below! Wow, that
was amazing. So many happy people.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into Tania and we went to the river where the Queen of the
Carnival was due to arrive - I ended up very tired so I went back for an
afternoon nap... I slept a hell of a lot too .. Waking up sometime
around 8pm, Tania and I walked back into town to eat and get on the
Internet.. The party was in full swing but I was not drinking tonight..
Tomorrow we have to travel to panama city and stay our last day at the
voyager hostel.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 14 - Back to Panama City&lt;br /&gt;
Its 7:20am in Penonomé.. Everyone here stayed up all night - so everyone
is sleeping while I'm thinking about breakfast! I leave the house and
headed for a walk - I walk up to the local Pio Pio store and ordered two
scambled egg combos (huevo revoulto) because I was so hungry. I took the
sausages back for Max, the family dog, to eat, and he loved them. I then
worked out the plans for travel with Tania - we would leave right away
on the bus and get to the hostel around 5pm. When we got there we met up
with some really cool Canadian/Dutch/Americans and headed back out for
carnival.. This version of carnival was much different than Penonomé -
this was Pamama City and it was massive!! People in this (possibly
million strong) crowd were throwing confetti on each other (this was the
small circle that is cut out of paper with a three-hole punch).. They
were also spraying some sort of foam out of cans to.. I was constantly
impressed by how nice and welcoming everyone was ... It was a great
party and I ended up drunk and had to stubble home on this one..  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 15 - Homeward Bound&lt;br /&gt;
Waking up after last nights craziness was cool - I did have to struggle
with confetti all over my body though , that was a real pain in the ass!
We checked out of the hostel, Tania went back to carnival for the day
and I went looking for food - I found a nice little place where I got
some amazing chicken fried rice ... For 2.95 I ended up with a plate
that would feed 5 people!!! I got a doggy bag to eat the rest at the
airport. I was looking forward to getting back home. My ride to the
airport would leave in a couple hours - grabbed two boxes of that cheap
wine for the road and headed back to the hostel. The flight home was
incredibly scary but I made it back! What's Next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TIl0BnPPeCI/AAAAAAAAADA/amIjvPOFBb0/s320/panama-flag.jpg" /&gt;]: http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TIl0BnPPeCI/AAAAAAAAADA/amIjvPOFBb0/s1600/panama-flag.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Panama"></category><category term="Travel"></category></entry><entry><title>The craziest nonsense of a song!</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/the-craziest-nonsense-of-a-song/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:31:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/the-craziest-nonsense-of-a-song/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I first learned of this song in the Dominican, my friend Davi was
playing it on his iPod and I remember someone telling me it was Daddy
Yankee. Fast forward to Panama, Tania shows me on her iPod the name of
the song "Danny Yankee - shakaron". I knew this song really by the crazy
mumbling! Well, after searching the internet I found out the real name
of the song "Macarron Chacarron" by El Chombo - love it or hate it, you
have to admit its different!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Music"></category></entry><entry><title>Panama Backpacker Style - 5</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/panama-backpacker-style-5/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:29:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/panama-backpacker-style-5/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 10 - Bye El Valle, hello Penonomé  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning returns and we all have decidedly less pep. No doubt, the
drinking had something to do with it. We all straggle up, Don gets milk
and we refresh the coffee demon. Packing and bussing ensues as we would
head out of El Valle and drop the guys off at the hotel's street in
Farillion. Tania and I stay on the bus and continue to a larger town
named Penonomé - the capital of the province of Coclé. This town is
filled with shops, I even managed to grab a panama flag here - now I
have picked up everything I need. There are all sorts of stores named
"Peter", Casa Peter, Mr Peter, Bla Bla Peter. At one very unusual
moment, I find Internet access while Tania tells me she's going to get
fries at Mr Peter. When I finish and go find her, she's nowhere to be
found! I take my time and walk up and down the street, I get fries of my
own and after about an hour, I decide to head back to the hotel. I was
wondering what the hell happened to her. It was a very interesting
process trying to explain to the man at the counter in the hotel that I
was in room 605 "Seesh, cero, sank-oo" and that I wanted to get into the
room without a key. After much sign language, probably a little bit of
dancing and poor Spanish, the man with the big ring of keys let me in. I
left a note for her and headed out back down the street. It was getting
dark so I was getting a bit worried. While walking back into town -
Tania was coming out of a mall. She had gone to do her nails. All was
fine at this point. We were off to Pio Pio to eat chicken.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panama 11 - Penonomé&lt;br /&gt;
All in all a low-key day in Penonomé... Not much more than shopping and
hanging out at the hotel, I managed to walk from one end of the town to
the other - the workers were clearly getting a large stage ready for
Carnaval.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panama 12 - Penonomé and Sona&lt;br /&gt;
Today, the Carnaval starts... There looked to be no chance to get to Las
Tablas so we made the decision we weren't going there. We found some
Americans that were willing to let us crash in their "crash pad", twelve
of them were in the room next to us. Then, Tania found something better!
Professor Ortiz - a local teacher in Penonomé - was willing to rent a
room in his house. Sweet. We headed over there and dropped our bags and
headed to my MAIN point of interest in Panama - Sona (well known for the
location of the key prison in the show Prison Break). The 200km bus ride
would cost no more than three bucks, but take a good three hours each
way, we needed to get on two different busses. Once in Sona it was clear
that this small town had no clue what type of fame has been brought to
them, or why. While asking a police officer to take a picture with me,
the description of the TV show "Prison Break" elicited deep, blank
stares. They would end up saying a forceful no to any sort of pictures.
I ended up with a picture at a local bank that said Sona. We stopped at
a local chicken place for amazing rotisserie and then jumped on the bus
back to Penonomé ...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus to Santiago was cool, but the bus from there to Penonomé was
horrible! It was impossible to see out the windows to tell where you
were - or even to tell if you had gotten to Penonomé , or if you were
actually there. Tania asked again and we finally made it to where we
were going.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right when we returned we connected with Kimmie an Jesus be checked out
the Carnaval that was going on.. It wasn't busy yet, but the people were
coming in to town in droves. I cut the night short because I wasn't
feeling so good.. Back to Prof Ortiz house...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TIlzEboa6CI/AAAAAAAAACw/ZrsR-U7EOQc/s320/panama-flag.jpg" /&gt;]: http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TIlzEboa6CI/AAAAAAAAACw/ZrsR-U7EOQc/s1600/panama-flag.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Panama"></category><category term="Travel"></category></entry><entry><title>Panama Backpacker Style - 4</title><link href="http://calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc/articles/panama-backpacker-style-4/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T01:28:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Kevin Costain (noreply@blogger.com)</name></author><id>tag:calwell.github.io/kevin.cwl.cc,2011-01-21:articles/panama-backpacker-style-4/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
[![image][]][]

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 7 - "The People"&lt;br /&gt;
Last night was a little crazy, the Clos wine was a big part of that or
"crack in a box" as it would be coined. Tania would get right drunk on
that stuff. My experience in the hammock was not all that good either -
the locals were really partying and I was being eaten by some sort of
painful bugs.. They bit my entire left arm but didn't touch my right
arm, weird. Tania woke me up at 8am with coffee and breakfast. I was not
ready to wake up and she said "Kev, You have to wake up!" - I thought it
was an emergency. When I finally woke up, we were off. There were two
couples of Americans down for a road trip that were really cool and let
us park our bags in their trailer while we were gone. Since the beach
was not going to connect us to the resort (it was right around the
point) - we were going to have to take a water taxi or a bus. We chose
the bus. After a couple short bus rides we were just outside the
Decamron complex. Walking up to the resort on the beach, we met a few of
the folks we knew and they would help in the process of obtaining a day
pass - that was $54.00. It was Pricey but part of the process if we
wanted to stay. We went into the pools , met and hung out with many of
the group members - Tim and Christine were nice enough to offer to let
me stay the night as well as a hot shower, that was nice! We would all
get to the large reservation in the Italian restaurant and party a bit.
I turned in early. Our next plan was getting out at 6am and heading to
El Valle. Our wrist bags only lasted till 2am and I didn't know for sure
where where Tania was staying....&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 8 - Hello El Valle&lt;br /&gt;
6am comes and Tim's alarm goes off. I gather my limited amount of stuff
and wait for Tania. After not hearing from her for 40 min I head out to
look for her. She ends up being easy to find and we walk out the front
door of the resort as inconspicuously as possible. There were a few
people that were coming with is on this trip and we were supposed to
meet them at the Santa Clara bus stop in a few hours. We went back to
the campground, grabbed our bags and then headed up to the bus stop more
than an hour early. A long wait to be sure... When they arrive I was
surprised to see how many people decided to come out! Jimmy, Don, Dennis
and Tom all made the trek. We all grabbed a bus - and I even took my
second still picture on this trip to El Valle. This time we would shack
up in a small spot called "Cabanas Pitosi", the room had three beds and
space for two hammocks outside. Once we were situated we headed for the
canopy tour. It was a steep $52.50, but everyone was in and it looked
well worth the price. We all hiked up the side of a mountain and then
zip-lined back down at three points between the trees, at times close to
180ft off the ground. One line was amazing! We were stopped right above
a waterfall halfway across. The view was unbelievable! We also saw
rubber trees and a possible Tucan sighting, though he didn't stick
around. Dennis and Tom decided to return home and Jimmy, Don, Tania and
I headed back to the room, got drunk and slept.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 9 - El Valle&lt;br /&gt;
So, I was in a hammock last night at "Cabanas Pitosi" - the one
noticeable thing being how cold it was - but I slept ok. Everyone else
stayed inside the cabin. We woke up to breakfast in bed thanks to Don
and Tania walking to the town for us, it was great! More exploring
needed to happen today though. We all walked into town and rented
bicycles, and then hit the road towards the golden frogs and the square
trees. There were very few golden frogs, but the square tress required
us to follow this great little "sendero". Along the way we came across
these leaf cutter ants.. They were all walking along a path, in one
direction carrying pieces of leaves, in the other direction going back,
this was incredibly organized. After getting to the square trees we
headed to the "pozos de thermale" or thermal pools.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea about the thermal pool is that there is water in a basin being
heated by the lava of the dormant volcano of El Valle. The water in the
pools was indeed incredibly warm to the touch. After paying the $1
entrance fee and seeing the pool - I personally decided to sit it out,
it looked pretty nasty. Don, Tania and Jimmy jumped in and seemed to
really enjoy it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this time Don and Jimmy were considering going back to the resort -
Tania did convince them to stay for a drink at the cabins before going.
When they decided to leave, it was so late in the town that everything
was shut down - the only way to get to the main highway was by taxi, and
they were charging $35 to get back to the resort. Somehow, I totally
missed the pivotal moment, but the decision was to stay another night...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="image" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TIly0yK-16I/AAAAAAAAACo/annGkrtL4yo/s320/panama-flag.jpg" /&gt;]: http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ND7dT2FzfL8/TIly0yK-16I/AAAAAAAAACo/annGkrtL4yo/s1600/panama-flag.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Panama"></category><category term="Travel"></category></entry></feed>